Guide to the David Low Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1916-63; Series II; 2.75; (7 boxes)
  - SHORTER WORKS
    - Letters to the Editor, Published: Individuals
      - Low, David, ca. 1930s, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 810)
      - Lunn, Arnold, 1944 Jun (Box 19, Folder 811)
      - Woodlock, Francis, 1937 Oct 20 (Box 19, Folder 812)
    - Radio Scripts: Single Programs
      The following materials are arranged chronologically.
      - Recording for "Scrapbook for 1923": typescript, corrected, 1923 Mar 21 (Box 19, Folder 813)
      - "To One of My So-called Victims"
        - Draft A, typescript, corrected, 1932 Dec 12 (Box 19, Folder 814)
        - Draft B, typescript and carbon, 1932 Dec 12 (Box 19, Folder 815)
      - "Letter C" broadcast: holograph and typescripts, ca. 1935 (Box 19, Folder 816)
      - "As I See It": typescripts, 1938 Dec 6 (Box 19, Folder 817)
      - Wartime "Cartoons in Sound", ca. 1939-45 (Box 19, Folder 818)
      - "Cartoonist's Work in Wartime"
        - Draft A, typescript, carbon, corrected, 1939 Oct 27 (Box 19, Folder 819)
        - Draft B, typescript, 1939 Oct 27 (Box 19, Folder 820)
      - "Artist in the Witness Box"
        - Draft A, typescript, carbon, corrected, 1940 Feb 5 (Box 19, Folder 821)
        - Draft B, typescript, carbon, 1940 Feb 5 (Box 19, Folder 822)
      - "Ersatz Greatness": typescript, 1941 Apr (Box 19, Folder 823)
      - "New Judgment: David Low on James Gillray"
        - Draft A, typescript, corrected, 1943 Nov 22 (Box 19, Folder 824)
        - Draft B, typescript, corrected and carbon, 1943 Nov 22 (Box 19, Folder 825)
        - Draft C, typescript, mimeograph, annotated, 1943 Nov 22 (Box 19, Folder 826)
      - "Five Minute Interview with David Low"
        - Typescript, carbons, 1944 Dec 15 (Box 19, Folder 827)
        - Typescript in French, mimeograph, corrected, 1944 Dec 15 (Box 19, Folder 828)
      - "Low on Laughter"
        - Typescript and carbon, corrected, 1944 Dec 28 (Box 19, Folder 829)
        - Typescript, mimeograph, 1944 Dec 28 (Box 19, Folder 830)
        - Typescript, mimeograph, annotated, 1944 Dec 28 (Box 19, Folder 831)
      - "Cinema for Fun"
        - Draft A, typescript and carbon, corrected, 1945 Apr 6 (Box 19, Folder 832)
        - Draft B, typescript, corrected, 1945 Apr 6 (Box 19, Folder 833)
      - "David Low and Quincy Howe": typescript and carbon, 1946 Sep 9 (Box 19, Folder 834)
      - "Art for Reform?": typescript and carbon, 1948 Feb 6 (Box 19, Folder 835)
      - "English Sense of Humour"
        - Draft A, typescript and holograph, 1949 Nov 29 (Box 19, Folder 836)
        - Draft B, typescript, 1949 Nov 29 (Box 19, Folder 837)
      - "'Krokodil' Cartoonists"
        - Draft A, typescript and carbon, corrected, 1950 Oct (Box 19, Folder 838)
        - Draft B, typescript, carbon, 1951 Feb 21 (Box 19, Folder 839)
      - "Changes in Humour over Fifty Years": typescript and carbon, 1951 Apr 2 (Box 19, Folder 840)
      - "Frankly Speaking": typescript, mimeograph and carbon, 1955 Jul 17 (Box 19, Folder 841)
      - "Low, Colonel Blimp, and the Horse"
        - No. 1 Low: typescript, mimeograph, 1958 Jan (Box 19, Folder 842)
        - No. 2 Colonel Blimp: typescript, mimeograph, 1958 Jan (Box 19, Folder 843)
        - No. 3 The Horse: typescript, mimeograph, 1958 Jan (Box 19, Folder 844)
      - "First Meeting No. 28: John Arlott and David Low": typescript, mimeograph, 1959 Aug 27 (Box 19, Folder 845)
      - "Piece for Ed Murrow's Program": typescript, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 846)
    - Radio Scripts: Serial Programs
      - "Democracy Marches"
        - Draft A, typescript, corrected, 1941 Jan 12/13 (Box 19, Folder 847)
        - Draft B, typescript, 1941 Jan 12/13 (Box 19, Folder 848)
        - Draft A, typescript, carbon, 1941 Jan 26/27 (Box 19, Folder 849)
        - Draft B, typescript, 1941 Jan 26/27 (Box 19, Folder 850)
        - Draft A, typescript, carbon, corrected, 1941 Feb 9/10 (Box 19, Folder 851)
        - Draft B, typescript, 1941 Feb 9/10 (Box 19, Folder 852)
        - Draft A, typescript, 1941 Mar 3/4 (Box 19, Folder 853)
        - Draft B, typescript, 1941 Mar 3/4 (Box 19, Folder 854)
        - Draft A, typescript, carbon, corrected, 1941 Feb 17/18 (Box 19, Folder 855)
        - Draft B, typescript, 1941 Feb 17/18 (Box 19, Folder 856)
        - Typescript, 1941 Mar 17/18 (Box 19, Folder 857)
        - Extracts from "Democracy Marches": typescript, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 858)
      - "Calling New Zealand"
        - Typescript, 1941 Mar 26 (Box 19, Folder 859)
        - "Calling New Zealand--A New Zealander on Westminster Bridge"
          - Draft A, typescript, ca. 1941 Mar (Box 19, Folder 860)
          - Draft B, typescript, corrected, ca. 1941 Mar (Box 19, Folder 861)
      - "Calling Australia and New Zealand"
        - Draft A, typescript, carbon, corrected, 1941 Jul 29 (Box 20, Folder 862)
        - Draft B, typescript, mimeograph, 1941 Jul 31 (Box 20, Folder 863)
        - Draft A, typescript, carbon, corrected, 1941 Aug 14 (Box 20, Folder 864)
        - Draft B, typescript, mimeograph, 1941 Aug 14 (Box 20, Folder 865)
        - Draft A, typescript, carbon, corrected, 1941 Aug 28 (Box 20, Folder 866)
        - Draft B, typescript, mimeograph, 1941 Aug 28 (Box 20, Folder 867)
        - Draft A, typescript, carbon, corrected, 1941 Sep 9 (Box 20, Folder 868)
        - Draft B, typescript, mimeograph, 1941 Sep 9 (Box 20, Folder 869)
        - Typescript, mimeograph, 1941 Sep 25 (Box 20, Folder 870)
        - Draft A, typescript, carbon, corrected, 1942 Jan 8 (Box 20, Folder 871)
        - Draft B, typescript, 1942 Jan 8 (Box 20, Folder 872)
        - Draft C, typescript, corrected, 1942 Jan 8 (Box 20, Folder 873)
        - Draft A, typescript and carbon, corrected, 1942 Feb 5 (Box 20, Folder 874)
        - Draft B, typescript, mimeograph, 1942 Feb 5 (Box 20, Folder 875)
        - Draft A, typescript and carbon, 1942 Mar 5 (Box 20, Folder 876)
        - Draft B, typescript, mimeograph, 1942 Mar 5 (Box 20, Folder 877)
        - Draft A, typescript and carbon, 1942 Apr 2 (Box 20, Folder 878)
        - Draft B, typescript, mimeograph, 1942 Apr 2 (Box 20, Folder 879)
        - Draft A, typescript, corrected, 1942 Apr 28 (Box 20, Folder 880)
        - Draft B, typescript and carbon, 1942 Apr 28 (Box 20, Folder 881)
        - Draft C, typescript, mimeograph, 1942 Apr 28 (Box 20, Folder 882)
        - Draft A, typescript and carbon, 1942 May 28 (Box 20, Folder 883)
        - Draft B, typescript, mimeograph, 1942 May 28 (Box 20, Folder 884)
        - Draft A, typescript and carbon, 1942 Jul 23 (Box 20, Folder 885)
        - Draft B, typescript, mimeograph, corrected, 1942 Jul 23 (Box 20, Folder 886)
        - Draft A, typescript and carbon, 1942 Aug 20 (Box 20, Folder 887)
        - Draft B, typescript, mimeograph, 1942 Aug 20 (Box 20, Folder 888)
        - Draft A, typescript, corrected, 1942 Sep 17 (Box 20, Folder 889)
        - Draft B, typescript and carbon, 1942 Sep 17 (Box 20, Folder 890)
        - Draft C, typescript, mimeograph, 1942 Sep 17 (Box 20, Folder 891)
        - Draft A, typescript and carbon, 1942 Oct 15 (Box 20, Folder 892)
        - Draft B, typescript, mimeograph, 1942 Oct 15 (Box 20, Folder 893)
        - Draft A, typescript and carbon, 1942 Nov 12 (Box 20, Folder 894)
        - Draft B, typescript, mimeograph, 1942 Nov 12 (Box 20, Folder 895)
        - Draft A, typescript and carbon, 1942 Dec 10 (Box 20, Folder 896)
        - Draft B, typescript, mimeograph, 1942 Dec 10 (Box 20, Folder 897)
        - Draft A, typescript and carbon, 1943 Feb 4 (Box 20, Folder 898)
        - Draft B, typescript, mimeograph, 1943 Feb 4 (Box 20, Folder 899)
        - Typescript; carbon; carbon, corrected, 1943 Mar 4 (Box 20, Folder 900)
        - Typescript; carbon; carbon, corrected, 1943 Apr 1 (Box 20, Folder 901)
        - Typescript; carbon; carbon, corrected, 1943 May [?] (Box 20, Folder 902)
        - Draft A, typescript, corrected, 1943 Jun [?] (Box 20, Folder 903)
        - Draft B, typescript; carbon; carbon, corrected, 1943 Jun [?] (Box 20, Folder 904)
      - "World Perspective"
        - Typescript, corrected and carbon, 1943 Jul 22 (Box 20, Folder 905)
        - Typescript, corrected and carbon, 1943 Aug 18 (Box 20, Folder 906)
        - Typescript and carbon, 1943 Sep 19 (Box 20, Folder 907)
        - Typescript, carbon, corrected and carbon, 1943 Oct 14 (Box 20, Folder 908)
        - Typescript and carbons, 1943 Nov 11 (Box 20, Folder 909)
        - Draft A, typescript and carbons, 1944 Jan 6 (Box 20, Folder 910)
        - Draft B, typescript, corrected and carbon, corrected, 1944 Jan 6 (Box 20, Folder 911)
        - Typescript, corrected and carbon, 1944 Feb 3 (Box 20, Folder 912)
        - Typescript, corrected and carbon, 1944 Mar 2 (Box 20, Folder 913)
        - Typescript and carbons, 1944 Apr 27 (Box 20, Folder 914)
        - Draft A, typescript, carbon, 1944 May 25 (Box 20, Folder 915)
        - Draft B, typescript and carbons, 1944 May 25 (Box 20, Folder 916)
        - Draft A, typescript, carbon, 1944 Jun 22 (Box 20, Folder 917)
        - Draft B, typescript and carbon, 1944 Jun 22 (Box 20, Folder 918)
        - Typescript and carbon, 1944 Jul (Box 20, Folder 919)
    - Research Files
      - Baldwin, Stanley, 1935 (Box 21, Folder 920)
      - Basis of All Arts, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 921)
      - Chamberlain, Austen, 1935 (Box 21, Folder 922)
      - Churchill, Winston, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 923)
      - Elements of Drawing by Ruskin, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 924)
      - Gandhi, Mahatma (Box 21, Folder 925)
      - Gillray and Caricature in the Georgian Era, Notes on, 1951 Aug 16 (Box 21, Folder 926)
      - Gillray and His Times, Notes on (Box 21, Folder 927)
      - Joynson-Hicks, William, Sir ("Jix"), n.d. (Box 21, Folder 928)
      - MacDonald, Ramsay, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 929)
      - Matters Artistic, Notes on, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 930)
      - Maugham, W. Somerset, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 931)
      - Nationality in Humour, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 932)
      - Nazism, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 933)
      - Notes, General, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 934-40)
      - U.S.S.R., n.d. (Box 21, Folder 941)
    - Speeches
      - "Address at the Exhibition of Drawings by Heath Robinson": typescript, corrected and carbon, 1945 Jan 23 (Box 21, Folder 942)
      - Address at the Opening of Exhibition of English Caricatures 1730-1831 at A.I.A. Gallery: typescript, 1956 Jul 6 (Box 21, Folder 943)
      - An Address Delivered at Convocation of the University of New Brunswick upon the Conferring of an Honorary Degree of Doctor of Laws: typescript and carbons, 1958 May 15 (Box 21, Folder 944)
        See also: Honors, Box 25, folder 1071
      - Address to Manchester Regional College of Art: typescript and carbon, 1959 Jul 2 (Box 21, Folder 945)
        See also: Honors, Box 25, folder 1069
      - Arms to Spain Meeting: typescript, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 946)
      - "Artists and Politics"
        - Notes, holograph and typescript (Box 21, Folder 947)
        - Draft A, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 948)
        - Draft B, typescript, 1941 Jul 30 (Box 21, Folder 949)
      - Artists General Benevolent Institution Royal Academy: typescript, 1945 Mar 7 (Box 21, Folder 950)
      - At Unveiling of Tombstone to James Gillray, St. James's Church, Piccadilly: notes, typescript; draft, typescript and carbon, 1961 Nov 16 (Box 21, Folder 951)
        See also: Draper Hill, Box 9, folder 476
      - Authors' Club: typescript, ca. 1935 (Box 21, Folder 952)
      - "Caricatures and Modern Society"
        - Notes, typescript, corrected, 1949 (Box 21, Folder 953)
        - Draft, typescript and carbon, 1949 Jul 12 (Box 21, Folder 954)
      - "Caricaturist and King of a Pacific Island": typescript, annotated, 1955 May 20 (Box 21, Folder 955)
      - "Cartoons in Russia": typescript, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 956)
      - Chairman Introducing Guests at Foyle's Literary Luncheon: typescript and carbon (Box 21, Folder 957)
      - Discussion about the Position of Art in Society: typescript, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 958)
      - Evening Standard Farewell Dinner: typescript, annotated, 1950 Mar 10 (Box 21, Folder 959)
      - Evening Standard: typescript (Box 21, Folder 960)
      - Exhibition of Czechoslovak Cartoons by Z. K., Hoffmeister, Pelc, Stephen, and Trier at the Czechoslovak Institute, with M. Jan Masyryk [sic] in the Chair: typescript and carbon, 1945 Sep 23 (Box 21, Folder 961)
      - "The Function of the Cartoonist": typescript, corrected, 1935 Mar 22 (Box 21, Folder 962)
      - H. G. Wells Memorial Meeting
        - Tribute by David Low: typescript, mimeograph and typescript, carbon, corrected, 1946 Oct 30 (Box 21, Folder 963)
        - Tribute by G. D. H. Cole: typescript, mimeograph, 1946 Oct 30 (Box 21, Folder 964)
        - Tribute by Richard Gregory: typescript, mimeograph, 1946 Oct 30 (Box 21, Folder 965)
      - Howard Hotel Christmas Luncheons: typescripts, annotated, 1948, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 966)
      - League of Nations Union Luncheon: typescript, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 967)
      - Lecture to Literary Circle at National Liberal Club: typescript and carbon (Box 21, Folder 968)
      - Medical Profession: typescript, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 969)
      - N.L.C. Literacy Circle: notes, holograph and typescript; draft, typescript; menu, 1937 Nov 24 (Box 21, Folder 970)
      - Omar Khayyám Club
        - Notes, sketches, draft fragments: typescript, corrected, 1949, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 971)
        - President's Speech: typescript, corrected, 1936 Nov 19 (Box 21, Folder 972)
        - Vice President's Speech: typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 973)
      - Opening of Exhibition of New Zealand Art at New Zealand House: typescript and carbons, 2nd carbon corrected, 1949 Nov 1 (Box 21, Folder 974)
      - Opening Show of Gilbert Spencer's Drawings: typescript, annotated, 1944 (Box 21, Folder 975)
      - P.E.N. Club: typescript, 1932 Feb 14 (Box 21, Folder 976)
      - Ruskin Society, 1935 Jun 24 (Box 21, Folder 977)
      - "Satire and the War": typescript, corrected (Box 21, Folder 978)
      - Speech at the David Low Dinner of the Cartoonists Club: typescript and carbon, 1960 Nov 7 (Box 21, Folder 979)
        See also: Correspondence, Box 6, folder 282 and Honors, Box 25, folder 1073
      - Speech for Czechoslovakia: typescript, 1947 (Box 21, Folder 980)
      - Speech to Labour Members Dinner: typescript, corrected, 1947 Feb 11 (Box 21, Folder 981)
      - Unidentified, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 982-83)
    - Television Scripts
      The following materials are arranged alphabetically.
      - "Black and White": typescript, mimeograph, 1958 Nov 26 (Box 22, Folder 984)
      - "Black on White": typescript, mimeograph, 1955 Apr (Box 22, Folder 985)
      - Draft Talk on David Low for "Wisdom" Series, N.B.C. Television, New York, Producer James Nelson
        - Typescript, 1959 Sep 24 (Box 22, Folder 986)
        - Carbon, 1959 Sep 24 (Box 22, Folder 987)
      - Personal Impressions No. 8: typescript and mimeograph, 1951 Apr 21 (Box 22, Folder 988)
      - Script for Appearance in the Churchill Series, American Broadcasting Company: typescript, 1960 Nov 9 (Box 22, Folder 989)
      - Script of Cinema Talk on Russian Caricatures: typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 990)
      - Script of Talk while drawing for Television at Alexandra Palace: typescript and carbon, corrected, 1949 Feb 23 (Box 22, Folder 991)
      - Television Interview: Part of "Picture Page": typescript, annotated, 1936 Nov 16 (Box 22, Folder 992)
      - Television Programme in the Wisdom Series produced by James Nelson, National Broadcasting Corporation, New York: typescript, photocopy, corrected, 1960 (Box 22, Folder 993)
      - Television: typescript, corrected, 1947 Nov 10 (Box 22, Folder 994)
      - Television: typescript, 1947 Dec 31 (Box 22, Folder 995)
- Published Drawings, 1903-85; Series III; 1; (2 boxes)
  Series III, Published Drawings (Boxes 23-24), is divided into ten subseries: Christmas Cards, Defaced Clippings of Cartoons, Graphics, Leaflets, Magazine Drawings, Menu Cards, Newspaper Drawings, Posters, Works of Others, and Miscellany. These materials are arranged alphabetically within each subseries.
  - CHRISTMAS CARDS
    - Christmas Cards, 1927-51, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 996)
  - DEFACED CLIPPINGS OF CARTOONS
    See also: Oversize, Box 37, folder 1240
    - Defaced Clippings of Cartoons, 1920-49, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 997-1001)
  - LEAFLETS
    - Leaflets, ca. 1920s-40s (Box 23, Folder 1002)
  - GRAPHICS
    See: Oversize, Box 37, folder 1241
  - MAGAZINE DRAWINGS
    See also: Oversize, Box 34, folders 1170-76
    - Collier's, 1939-40 (Box 23, Folder 1003-04)
    - Competitions: A Magazine for Home Amusement and Instruction, 1912-14 (Box 23, Folder 1005-06)
    - Daylight, 1909 Jun 15 (Box 23, Folder 1007)
    - The Exhibition Sketcher, 1906-07 (Box 23, Folder 1008)
    - Fun and Fact, 1904 Dec (Box 23, Folder 1009)
    - Graphic, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 1010)
    - The Lone Hand, 1912-13 (Box 23, Folder 1011-12)
    - The Mirror, 1910 Nov (Box 23, Folder 1013)
    - Punch, 1923-27 (Box 23, Folder 1014)
    - Stead's, 1919 Mar 8 (Box 23, Folder 1015)
    - A Woman's Home Journal for Australasia, 1903 Sep 5 (Box 23, Folder 1016)
    - "The Younger Generation," Leader Magazine, 1949 (Box 23, Folder 1017-19)
  - MENU CARDS
    - National Liberal Club, 1927-33 (Box 24, Folder 1020)
    - Omar Khayyám Club, 1925-49 (Box 24, Folder 1021-23)
    - Parliamentary Press Gallery, 1925-46 (Box 24, Folder 1024)
    - Savage Club, 1928-35 (Box 24, Folder 1025)
    - The Sette of Odd Volumes, 1929-38 (Box 24, Folder 1026-27)
    - The Titmarsh Club, 1926-29 (Box 24, Folder 1028)
    - Miscellany, 1919-57 (Box 24, Folder 1029-30)
  - NEWSPAPER DRAWINGS
    See also: Oversize, Box 34, folders 1177-82; Box 38, folders 1249-60; Box 39, folders 1261-74; and Box 40, folders 1275-79
    - Musso the Dog in "Low's Weather Gauge," Star, 1926 (Box 24, Folder 1031-33)
    - "Pindar the Panda": Illustrations, Evening Standard, 1939 (Box 24, Folder 1034)
    - "Pindar the Panda": Illustrations with story, Evening Standard, 1939 (Box 24, Folder 1035-36)
    - Portrait Sketches, "London Letter," Manchester Guardian, 1957-62 (Box 24, Folder 1037-42)
    - Miscellany, 1941-59, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 1043)
  - POSTERS
    - "Colonel Blimp and Friends: The Cartoons of Sir David Low, 1891-1963", 1985 (Box 24, Folder 1043a)
    - "Don't You Remember Me?", ca. 1920s (Box 24, Folder 1043a)
    - "I Stand Before You as a Liberal Tory Anything", ca. 1920s (Box 24, Folder 1043a)
    - "Kept Home Fires Burning", ca. 1920s (Box 24, Folder 1043a)
    - "Look for Low", ca. 1920s (Box 24, Folder 1043a)
    - "The Midnight Watch: Wall Sheet of Britain's Fire Guard and Civil Defense Workers", ca. 1939 (Box 24, Folder 1043a)
    - "New Pups to Sell", ca. 1920s (Box 24, Folder 1043a)
    - "Paintings by Sir Winston Churchill", n.d. (Box 24, Folder 1043a)
    - "Puzzle: Find the 'Evening News'", ca. 1920s (Box 24, Folder 1043a)
    - "Veritasquith", ca. 1920s (Box 24, Folder 1043a)
    - "Vote Liberal: Come On! Steve!", ca. 1920s (Box 24, Folder 1043a)
    - "Vote Liberal: His Share of Protection", ca. 1920s (Box 24, Folder 1043a)
    - "Who Pushed the Taxpayer In?", ca. 1920s (Box 24, Folder 1043a)
    - "You Lost Your Money on This--Will You Win on Either of These?", ca. 1920s (Box 24, Folder 1043a)
  - WORKS OF OTHERS
    - Efimov, Boris, 1942 (Box 24, Folder 1044)
    - Nagy, István, 1938 (Box 24, Folder 1045)
    - Unidentified, ca. 1950s (Box 24, Folder 1046)
  - MISCELLANY
    See also: Oversize, Box 40, folder 1280
    - Miscellany, 1927-53, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 1047)
- Personal Papers, 1900-66; Series IV; 3.75; (9 boxes)
  Series IV, Personal Papers (Boxes 27-33), is divided into seven subseries: Biographical Materials; Correspondence Lessons in Art; Honors; Personal Press Clippings; Printed Material, Miscellaneous; Scrapbooks; and Works on Low. The materials within each subseries are arranged alphabetically except that within Personal Press Clippings, which is arranged chronologically.
  - BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIALS
    See also: Oversize, Box 40, folders 1281-83
    - Low, David Brown: obituary, 1937 (Box 25, Folder 1048)
    - Low, Rachel: miscellany, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 1049)
    - Motor Spirit Ration Book, 1939 Nov 21 (Box 25, Folder 1050)
    - Photographs of David Low as they appeared in various magazines and newspapers: part I, 1920-58, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 1051)
      See also: Oversize, Box 37, folder 1283
    - Photographs of A. P. Wadsworth, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 1052)
      See also: Correspondence, Box 7, folders 325-28
    - Sir David Low Cartoons: List of Originals Distributed from File at His Request of the Period 1-10-1941 - 30-4-1963 Inclusive (Box 25, Folder 1053)
    - War Correspondent's Temporary License and Temporary Accreditation to the Control Commission for Germany (British Element), 1945 Nov 28 (Box 25, Folder 1054)
    - Miscellany, 1915-37, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 1055)
  - CORRESPONDENCE LESSONS IN ART
    See also: Oversize, Box 35, folders 1184-96
    - International Correspondence Schools, 1900-03 (Box 25, Folder 1056-58)
    - The New York School of Caricature
      - Lesson nos. 1, 2, 3, 1903-06 (Box 25, Folder 1059)
      - Lesson nos. 4, 5, 6, 9, 1903-06 (Box 25, Folder 1060)
      - Sketches, 1903-06 (Box 25, Folder 1061-67)
    - Paige-Davis Correspondence School, 1904 (Box 25, Folder 1068)
  - HONORS
    - Honorary Degrees
      - Associateship, Regional College of Art, Manchester, 1959 (Box 25, Folder 1069)
        See also: Speeches, Box 21, folder 945
      - Doctor of Laws, University of Leicester, 1960-61 (Box 25, Folder 1070)
      - Doctor of Laws, University of New Brunswick, 1958 (Box 25, Folder 1071)
        See also: Speeches, Box 21, folder 944
    - Honorary Dinners
      - Dinner Given by Brother Artists on Low's Departing Australia, 1919 Aug 5 (Box 25, Folder 1072)
      - Dinner Given by the Cartoonists Club, 1960 (Box 25, Folder 1073)
        See also: Correspondence, Box 6, folder 282 and Speeches, Box 21, folder 979
    - Knighthood, 1962 (Box 25, Folder 1074)
  - PERSONAL PRESS CLIPPINGS
    - Scrapbooks
      See also: Oversize, Box 35, folders 1197-1200 and Box 40, folder 1284
      - Book nos. 1-3, 1902-29 (Box 26, Folder 1075-77)
      - Book nos. 4-5, 1929-32 (Box 27, Folder 1078-79)
      - Book no. 5: loose clippings, 1932 (Box 27, Folder 1080)
      - Book no. 6, 1932-33 (Box 27, Folder 1081)
      - Book nos. 7-9, 1932-38 (Box 28, Folder 1082-84)
      - Book no. 10, 1938-40 (Box 29, Folder 1085)
      - Book no. 11, 1939-41 (Box 29, Folder 1086)
        See also: Oversize, Box 35, folder 1197
      - Book no. 12, 1942-44 (Box 29, Folder 1087)
      - Book no. 12: loose clippings, part I, 1943 (Box 30, Folder 1088)
        See also: Oversize, Box 35, folder 1198
      - Book no. 13, 1944-47 (Box 30, Folder 1089)
        See also: Oversize, Box 35, folder 1199
      - Book no. 14, 1947-50 (Box 30, Folder 1090)
      - Book no. 14: loose clippings, part I, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 1091)
        See also: Oversize, Box 40, folder 1284
      - Book no. 15, 1950-52 (Box 31, Folder 1092)
      - Book no. 15: loose clippings, 1952 Jul 6 (Box 31, Folder 1093)
      - Book no. 16, 1953-57 (Box 31, Folder 1094)
      - Book no. 16: loose clippings, 1956 (Box 32, Folder 1095)
      - Book no. 17, 1956-62 (Box 32, Folder 1096)
      - Book no. 17: loose clippings, 1957 (Box 32, Folder 1097)
      - Book no. 18, 1962-63 (Box 32, Folder 1098)
      - Book no. 19 [obituaries of David Low]
        See: Oversize, Box 35, folder 1200
    - Loose Clippings
      See also: Oversize, Box 40, folders 1285-86
      - 1910s, 1919, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 1099)
        See also: Oversize, Box 40, folder 1285